Guide to the Carl Feiss papers, [ca.1928]-1991
Feiss, Carl papers, [ca.1928]-1991
- Series II. Professional Papers
  - Organizations
    - National Trust for Historic Preservation: Board of Trustees/Executive Committee: correspondence, meeting minutes, budget report, brochure for Red Lion Inn., 1969-1970 (Box 18, Folder 33)
    - National Trust for Historic Preservation: restoration of the West Front of the United States Capitol: correspondence, field report, statement, clippings., 1969-1970 (Box 18, Folder 34)
    - National Trust for Historic Preservation: Board of Trustees/Executive Committee: meeting agenda, meeting minutes, list of members., 1969 (Box 18, Folder 35)
    - National Trust for Historic Preservation: Field Service Committee: list of members, bi-monthly reports, "Consultant Services Program: Grants Awarded Since July 1969," revised proposed fiscal year 1971 budget, "Preliminary Properties Consideration Report," budget draft, memoranda, brochure., 1969-1970 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - National Trust for Historic Preservation: Membership Services Committee: field reports, correspondence, proposed budget, financial statements, brochure for Historic Savannah Foundation, Inc., "Digest of Cases: Advisory Council on Historic Preservation," "Architectural Surveys,", 1970 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - National Trust for Historic Preservation: Nominating Committee: meeting minutes, correspondence, memoranda., 1969-1970 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - National Trust for Historic Preservation: Denver, Colorado: correspondence; clippings; 1970 meeting schedule; list of officers; list of committees; 23rd Annual Meeting and Preservation Conference, Denver, Colorado, October 2-5, 1969: announcement, meeting minutes, program, list of registrants, "Brief Biographies of Speakers," meeting agenda, list of Feiss' conference expenses., 1969-1970 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - National Trust for Historic Preservation: Field Services Committee: memoranda, correspondence, meeting agenda, list of members, clippings., 1969 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - National Trust for Historic Preservation: Field Services Committee: meeting agenda, correspondence, clippings, field reports, "Proposed Historic Preservation Enabling Bill for Municipalities and Counties," "Suggested Law to Authorize State Participation In National Historic Preservation Act," "Program for the Physical Improvement of a Neighborhood," "Report to the Permanent Headquarters Committee: El Paso Historical Society," memoranda., 1969 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - National Trust for Historic Preservation: International Relations Committee: correspondence, meeting agenda, meeting minutes, memorandum., 1969 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - National Trust for Historic Preservation: Board of Trustees/Executive Committee: list of members, "Financial Statements and Supplementary Information, Year Ended June 30, 1968," "Report of Committee on Professional and Public Education for Historic Preservation to the Trustees of the National Trust for Historical Preservation," clippings, meeting agendas, brochure for Fort Pulaski, National Monument, Georgia., 1968-1969 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - National Trust for Historic Preservation: Board of Trustees/Executive Committee: meeting minutes, correspondence, press release, memoranda, meeting agenda, meeting schedule, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - National Trust for Historic Preservation: Board of Trustees/Executive Committee: catalog of publications from "National Trust and Others, 1967-1968;" brochure for "The Registry of National Historic Landmarks;" fiscal year 1969 budget; meeting agenda; list of HUD film booking requests; memoranda; meeting minutes; 10th Seminar for Historical Administrators, Williamsburg, Virginia, June 16-July 26, 1968: biographies of student participants; "policy matters relative to 1968-1969 budget for membership services, schedule of meetings. (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - National Trust for Historic Preservation: International Relations Committee, Urban Design Committee, Board of Trustees/Executive Committee: Exposition sur la Medina de Tunis: quelques elements d'analyse de son evolution, Tunis: program, poster; correspondence, memoranda, meeting minutes, "Federal Programs for Historic Preservation," press release., 1967-1968 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - National Trust for Historic Preservation: Board of Trustees/Executive Committee: brochure for Testamentary Gift Program, annual report, meeting minutes, correspondence, memoranda, "Urban Planning Assistance Program," list of membership services, telegram., 1967-1968 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - National Trust for Historic Preservation: Housing and Urban Development: "Urban Planning Assistance Program," memorandum, "HUD Grants for Historic Preservation.", 1968 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - National Trust for Historic Preservation: Historic Preservation: correspondence, drafts., 1967-1968 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - National Trust for Historic Preservation: Board of Trustees/Executive Committee: memoranda, Preservation News, March 1967. (front page article "Members' Meeting Called On Revised Principles And Guidelines, By-Laws." (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - National Trust for Historic Preservation: Board of Trustees/Executive Committee: receipt; clippings; "The Nongovernmental Organization at Bay;" 21st Annual Meeting and Preservation Conference, Saint Louis, Missouri, October 19-22, 1967: program, registration form, "A Proposal for the Implementation of the Whitehill Committee Report," "Report of Committee on Professional and Public Education for Historic Preservation to the Trustees of the National Trust for Historic Preservation," "Report of the International Relations Committee," meeting schedule, correspondence, meeting minutes, memoranda. (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - National Trust for Historic Preservation: Board of Trustees/Executive Committee: memoranda, meeting minutes, treasurer's report, organizational constitution, finance policy, "Sites, Building and Objects: Policy and Procedure," "Policies Relating to National Trust Historic Properties/Policies on Admission Fees at National Trust Historical Properties," "Master Plan for Belle Grove," publications property, "Charter for the Decauter House Council of the National Trust for Historic Preservation," "Financial Statements and Supplementary Information Year Ended June 30, 1967." (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - National Trust for Historic Preservation: Preservation News, March 1967. (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - National Trust for Historic Preservation: Report on Principles and Guidelines for Historic Preservation in the United States: correspondence re: contract to publish., 1967 (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - National Trust for Historic Preservation: Awards Committee: correspondence, meeting minutes, awards program policy, list of 1966 Louise Du Pont Crowninshield Award Nominees., 1966-1967 (Box 19, Folder 20)
    - National Trust for Historic Preservation: Board of Trustees/Executive Committee: meeting minutes., 1967 (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - National Trust for Historic Preservation: HUD Film Project (Housing and Urban Development): script drafts, correspondence., 1968 (Box 19, Folder 22)
    - National Trust for Historic Preservation: International Relations Committee: guidelines, meeting agendas., 1967 (Box 19, Folder 23)
    - National Trust for Historic Preservation: Bylaws Committee: meeting reminder, memoranda, proposed change in the bylaws, correspondence, list of officers, list of standing advisory committees, report of the International Relations Committee, organizational constitution., 1967-1968 (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - National Trust for Historic Preservation: 20th Annual Meeting and Preservation Conference, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, October 6-9, 1966: program, annual report, memorandum, reservation form. (Box 19, Folder 25)
    - National Trust for Historic Preservation: 20th Annual Meeting and Preservation Conference, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, October 6-9, 1966: Awards Committee: special report; brochure on The Preservation Congress; Preservation News, February 1967; Texas Sunday Magazine, February 20, 1966; memoranda, correspondence. (Box 19, Folder 26)
    - National Trust for Historic Preservation: Board of Trustees/Executive Committee: meeting minutes, correspondence, memoranda., 1966 (Box 19, Folder 27)
    - National Trust for Historic Preservation: Capitol Expansion: correspondence, "discussion draft" of "A Bill to establish a Commission on Architecture and Planning for the Capitol," clipping., 1966 (Box 19, Folder 28)
    - National Trust for Historic Preservation: Key Statement: National Trust Fund., 1966 (Box 19, Folder 29)
    - National Trust for Historic Preservation: Properties Committee: memorandum, "Preservation of Historic Properties," correspondence., 1966 (Box 19, Folder 30)
    - National Trust for Historic Preservation: "A Report on Principles and Guidelines for Historic Preservation in the United States," memorandum, "The National Trust for Historic Preservation: A Statement of Principles.", 1964 (Box 19, Folder 31)
    - National Trust for Historic Preservation: National Trust Properties; clippings; 1966-1967 Annual Report; The National Trust for places of Historic Interest or Natural Beauty, Spring 1966; National Trust Properties 1966 Opening Arrangements; "Combined Financial Statements and Supplementary Information Year Ended June 30, 1965;" 1965 Program of Work, memoranda, membership statistics, proposed 1966 budget, "Charter for Lyndhurst Council of the National Trust for Historic Preservation.", 1965-1966 (Box 19, Folder 32)
    - National Trust for Historic Preservation: Board of Trustees/Executive Committee: correspondence, memoranda, list of advisory committee members, biographies., 1965-1966 (Box 19, Folder 33)
    - National Trust for Historic Preservation: bylaws., 1965 (Box 19, Folder 34)
    - National Trust for Historic Preservation: Properties Committee: meeting agenda, bylaws, proposal for restoration and preservation of Historic Buildings, memoranda, correspondence, materials re: opening of the Pope-Leighey House, Woodlawn Plantation, Mount Vernon, Virginia, June 16, 1965., 1965-1966 (Box 19, Folder 35)
    - National Trust for Historic Preservation: Board of Trustees/Executive Committee: meeting agenda; 18th Annual Meeting and Preservation Conference, San Antonio, Texas, October 29-November 1, 1964: registration form; correspondence, memoranda, program of work, editorial policy, miscellaneous Trust publicity, list of publications. (Box 19, Folder 36)
    - National Trust for Historic Preservation: Properties Committee: memoranda; correspondence; inventory of Lady Gosford's House in South Shaftsbury, Vermont; proposed budget for the Decatur House, 1965; proposed budget for Woodlawn, 1965; program of work; objects policy; "policy on the use of National Trust properties for special events;" combined statement budget and actual, 1964; proposed alterations to Decature House; meeting agenda. (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - National Trust for Historic Preservation: Bylaws Committee: correspondence, bylaw drafts., 1963-1964 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - New York State Historical Association: 17th Annual Seminars on American Culture, Cooperstown, New York, July 5-18, 1964: brochure and registration form; 18th Annual Seminars on American Culture, Cooperstown, New York, July 4-17, 1965: brochure and registration form; "1964 Report of the Joint Legislative Committee on Metropolitan Areas Study; correspondence; The Society for the Preservation of Landmarks in Western New York, June 1964; catalogue of the History Museum Training and American Folklore Culture, 1964-1965. (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Newark Group: correspondence, memoranda., 1964-1965 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Old Post Office Landmark Committee: correspondence, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Old Post Office Landmark Committee: clippings, correspondence, list of members, "testimony on the preservation of the Old St. Louis Post Office Building," statistics of the building., 1968-1970 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Planning Foundation of America: correspondence, memorandum., 1970 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Planning Foundation of America: correspondence, "Arrangements for Project to Develop Methods for Estimating Recreation Demand in a Metropolitan Region," meeting minutes, list of board of directors, meeting agenda, memoranda, "Modeling Recreation Use in a Metropolitan Region.", 1969 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Planning Foundation of America: memoranda, "An Annotated Bibliography Outdoor Recreation Demand Literature," correspondence, draft of study proposal "Development of Methods for Estimating Recreation Demand in a Metropolitan Region.", 1968 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Planning Foundation of America: memorandum, list of board of directors, clippings, bylaws, articles of incorporation., 1968 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Planning Foundation of America: meeting minutes, memoranda, correspondence, "Summary of Suggestions for Foundation Projects," meeting agenda., 1967 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Planning Foundation of America: meeting minutes, memoranda, correspondence, "Nature of Proposed Activities, May 1965," proposed bylaws, "A Detailed Statement of Proposed Activities," certificate of incorporation. (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Society of Architectural Historians: list of available publications; prepublication offer; brochure of Washington, D.C. Southwest; Society of Architectural Historians' Annual Meeting, Chicago, Illinois, January 38-31, 1971: preliminary program; brochure for Reston, Virginia; materials re: Washington Committee for the 1970 SAH Annual Meeting., 1968-1975 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Society of Architectural Historians: newsletters, membership forms, organizational brochure, corerpondence., 1967 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Society of Architectural Historians: SAH Architectural Tour, Caribbean, June 11-24, 1967: announcement, registration form; newsletter, list of available publications. (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Society of Architectural Historians: Annual Meeting, New York, January 27-28, 1966: program, memoranda, advance registration list, preliminary program, correspondence., 1965-1966 (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - Town and Country Alliance: correspondence, remarks by C.D. Ward to the National Advisory Committee on Rural Areas Development, March 26, 1968. (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - Tregaron: correspondence, list of steering committee members, "Responsibilities of Particular Members of Steering Committee as Agreed to at Meeting of September 28, 1968," "Tregaron Plan Concept," clipping. (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - Union Internationale des Architectes: correspondence, "The Architect, the Environment and the World," clippings, memoranda, "La Formation de l'Urbaniste," meeting minutes., 1970 (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - Union Internationale des Architectes: The Plenary Sessions: "Open Space:" "Union Internationale des Architectes Commission for Town Planning," "Les Espaces Libres Dans La Ville," "Open Space for Human Needs," news release, remarks by D. Rettie, director of Open Space and Urban Beautification Division, "The Regional Imperative," clippings, notes, "membership and functions of work groups," "Towards Quality of the Metropolitan Environment," remarks by Samuel C. Jackson, Assistant Secretary for Metropolitan Planning and Development, congressional attendees of capitol luncheon, September 23, 1970. (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - Union Internationale des Architectes: Town Planning Commission., 1969-1970 (Box 20, Folder 21)
    - Union Internationale des Architectes: notification of Feiss' resignation as the United States' representative on the UIA Commission for Town Planning., 1969 (Box 20, Folder 22)
    - Union Internationale des Architectes: correspondence., 1968 (Box 20, Folder 23)
    - Union Internationale des Architectes: list of Town Planning Commission members; correspondence; newsletter; questionnaire; meeting schedule; Symposium, Innsbruck, 1968: program; meeting minutes; "Report to Committee on International Relations AIA on Board of Directors Conference, Pan American Federation of Architects, San Juan, Puerto Rico, January 21-23, 1968; 9th Congres UIA 67 Prague: program; budget estimate for UIA Town Planning Commission Meeting in Washington, D.C., 1970 or 1971., 1967-1968 (Box 20, Folder 24)
    - Union Internationale des Architectes: correspondence., 1968-1969 (Box 20, Folder 25)
    - Union Internationale des Architectes: correspondence., 1968 (Box 20, Folder 26)
    - Union Internationale des Architectes: correspondence, "Report on World Congress of Architects in Prague.", 1967 (Box 20, Folder 27)
    - Union Internationale des Architectes: correspondence, meeting minutes., 1967 (Box 20, Folder 28)
    - Union Internationale des Architectes: travel itinerary, correspondence, memroranda, "The Historic Heritage in the Modern World.", 1967 (Box 20, Folder 29)
    - Union Internationale des Architectes: correspondence and receipts re: expenses for Feiss' trip to Prague., 1967 (Box 20, Folder 30)
    - Union Internationale des Architectes: materials re: reorganization., 1967 (Box 20, Folder 31)
    - Union Internationale des Architectes: brochures and program for 9th Congres UIA in Prague., 1967 (Box 20, Folder 32)
    - Union Internationale des Architectes: clippings; "A Few of the Problems of Large Scale Housing Developments in Relation to the Total Urban Environment, June 28-July 7, 1967; working group "F;" "registration for Prague conference; "L'Heritage historique dans le monde moderne." (Box 20, Folder 33)
    - Union Internationale des Architectes: correspondence., 1965-1966 (Box 20, Folder 34)
    - Union Internationale des Architectes: Inter-Regional Seminar on Development Policies and Planning in Relation to Urbanization: "Urban Policies and Programmes in the United States," "Urbanization and National Development: Some Approaches to the Dilemma," correspondence, summary of "Social Policies and Planning in Relation to Urban Growth and Population Decentralization; Population Concentration and Movements and the Distribution of Social Services; Geographical Strategy in Social Planning," clippings, tentative agenda and schedule of meetings., 1966 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Union Internationale des Architectes: Town Planning Commission, RIBA (Royal Institute of British Architects), May 23-27, 1966: list of members, correspondence, notes, press release, meeting minutes, "Draft of questionnaire by the UIA Permanent Town Planning Committee for the preparation of the studies carried on by the working groups London meeting, May 1966," "Preparation of the 9th UIA Congress, Prague 1967." (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Union Internationale des Architectes: Town Planning Commission, RIBA (Royal Institute of British Architects), May 23-27, 1966: notes from working group A, correspondence, Ten Years of Housing in Sheffield, 1962., 1962-1966 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Union Internationale des Architectes: Town Planning Commission, RIBA (Royal Institute of British Architects), May 23-27, 1966: summary of fourth session discussion, May 25; correspondence; clippings. (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Union Internationale des Architectes: Town Planning Commission: RIBA (Royal Institute of British Architects): Working Group E: "The Historic Heritage in the Modern World," list members, correspondence, draft report., 1966 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Urban America, Inc.: brochures, "The Turning Point," correspondence, press release, announcement of annual meeting, proposed bylaws, "The History of Planned New Towns in the United States.", 1969 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Urban America, Inc.: press releases; "Our People in Their Cities:" A Conference of Urban America, Washington, D.C., September 12, 1966: keynote address; correspondence; Emergency Convocation: The Urban Coalition, Washington, D.C., August 24, 1967: published proceedings., 1966-1967 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Urban America, Inc.: brochures, correspondence., 1966-1967 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - World Future Society: announcement of meetings; photograph of Feiss, March 1968. (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Projects
    - ACIR (Advisory Commission on Intergovernmental Relations): "Intergovernmental Policies for Urbanization and New Community Development: Conclusions and Recommendations (Revised)," Washington, D.C., April 5, 1968. (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - ACIR (Advisory Commission on Intergovernmental Relations): correspondence, "recommendations referring to state and regional planning excerpted from two recent reports," "State and Regional Planning.", 1968 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - ACIR (Advisory Commission on Intergovernmental Relations): Balanced Urbanization and New Community Development: "Chapter 1: The Pattern of Urbanization," "Chapter 2: Regional Economic Growth," cover letter sent to critics, list of critics., 1967 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - ACIR (Advisory Commission on Intergovernmental Relations): Balanced Urbanization and New Community Development: "Chapter 3: Guiding Future Urbanization and Economic Growth," "Chapter 4: New Communities in America and Their Objectives.", 1967 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - ACIR (Advisory Commission on Intergovernmental Relations): Balanced Urbanization and New Community Development: "Chapter 5: Building New Communities in America.", 1967 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - ACIR (Advisory Commission on Intergovernmental Relations): Balanced Urbanization and New Communities Development: "Chapter 6: Conclusions and Recommendations.", 1967 (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - ACIR (Advisory Commission on Intergovernmental Relations): new towns legislation, 1967-1969 (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - ACIR (Advisory Commission on Intergovernmental Relations): press releases, correspondence, prospectus for "New Towns study," "Outline of Study of Balanced Urbanization and New Community Development," memoranda., 1964-1967 (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - Alexandria, Virginia: Gadsby Commercial Urban Renewal Project: city of Alexandria annual report and civic calendar, correspondence, city layouts., 1967 (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - [empty] (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - American Revolution Bicentennial Commission: correspondence, memoranda, clippings, Rhode Island: A Guide to the Arts 5, "Report to the President, July 4, 1970." (Box 21, Folder 20)
    - American Revolution Bicentennial Commission: correspondence, news releases, clippings, notes for proposal, "A Proposal for The American Revolution Bicentennial Celebration," list of consultants., 1970 (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - Annapolis, Maryland: Historic Annapolis, Inc.: correspondence, "Report on Architectural Styles in Historic Annapolis, Maryland.", 1971-1973 (Box 21, Folder 22)
    - Atlanta, Georgia: Model Cities Program, Urban Design Framework: notes, correspondence, memoranda, "Atlanta Model Cities Program, Work Elements for an Urban Environmental Design for the Model Cities Area," "Answers to Proposal for Initial Design Concepts.", 1969-1970 (Box 21, Folder 23)
    - Atlanta, Georgia: Model Cities Program, Urban Design Framework: correspondence., 1966-1967 (Box 21, Folder 24)
    - Augusta, Georgia: Central Savannah River Area Planning and Development Commission: clippings, brochures, correspondence., 1966 (Box 21, Folder 25)
    - Augusta, Georgia: Central Savannah River Area Planning and Development Commission: clippings, brochures, Augusta, city layouts., 1966 (Box 21, Folder 26)
    - Baltimore, Maryland: Advisory Committee on Housing Law Enforcement: list of members, "proposed amendments to ordinance city council no. 286," memoranda, "Ordinance and Regulations Governing the Hygiene of Housing.", 1964 (Box 21, Folder 27)
    - Baltimore, Maryland: "Final Report of the Mayor's Study Committee on Housing Law Enforcement," "Task Force Recommendations on Procedure for Implementation of the Wolman Committee Report Proposals for the Reorganization of the Department of Public Works.", 1963-1964 (Box 21, Folder 28)